So far in this lesson we've been focusing on one expression for each situation in this one.
到目前为止，在本课中，我们一直专注于针对这一情况的每种情况的一种表达方式。
In this situation I want to share a couple because there are a couple different ones that are really
在这种情况下，我想分享一对，因为有几个不同的
relevant to this situation and can be used in other places as well.
与这种情况相关，也可以在其他地方使用。
OK so you're relying on your parents for money that means you don't have your own money.
好的，所以你依靠你的父母来赚钱，这意味着你没有自己的钱。
Maybe you don't have a job.
也许你没有工作。
You can't find a decent job to support yourself.
你找不到体面的工作来养活自己。
Support yourself means you can buy your own food you can pay your own rent can buy your own clothes.
养活自己意味着您可以购买自己的食物 您可以支付自己的房租 可以购买自己的衣服。
This is what it means to support yourself.
这就是养活自己的意思。
Well very simply if you want to express that you don't have money we often just say that I'm broke I'm
非常简单，如果你想表达你没有钱，我们经常只是说我破产了
totally broke.
完全崩溃了。
B R O K E broke Hey do you want to go get a drink.
B R O K E 坏了 嘿，你想去喝一杯吗？
No I can't.
不，我不能。
Why not.
为什么不。
I'm broke.
我破产了。
I have no money.
我没钱。
Oh I'll lend you 20 dollars.
哦，我借给你20美元。
No no that's OK.
不不，没关系。
I don't want to borrow any money I'm broke to stay home.
我不想借任何我破产的钱呆在家里。
OK so being broke is not fun having no money is not fun but it's a common expression and sometimes people
好吧，所以破产不好玩没钱不好玩，但这是一种常见的表达方式，有时人们
add if it's really a bad situation flat FFO a t flat broke after my vacation to Japan.
补充一下，如果情况真的很糟糕，我去日本度假后，FFO 公寓就坏了。
I was flat broke.
我破产了。
I had to save up for two years before I could take another trip.
我必须存两年的钱才能再去一次旅行。
OK can be used in a lot of different cases where you want to say that you don't have any money left
OK可以用在很多不同的情况下，你想说你没有钱了
right now when we're in this situation where you rely on your parents at least in America.
现在，当我们处于这种情况下，您至少在美国依靠父母。
I know in some countries relying on your parents and getting money from your parents is fine.
我知道在一些国家，依靠你的父母并从你父母那里得到钱是可以的。
It's not an issue.
这不是问题。
Well in America it is.
在美国是这样。
I read a news story about a man who was 30 years old and hadn't moved out of his parent's home and was
我读到一个新闻报道，一个 30 岁的男子还没有搬出他父母的家，
sued by his parents for not leaving.
被父母起诉不离开。
So this is kind of American culture you've got to get out and support yourself as soon as possible maybe
所以这是一种美国文化，你必须尽快走出去养活自己，也许
even as young as 18 years old.
甚至年仅18岁。
Really.
真的。
Yes.
是的。
It's kind of American culture.
这是一种美国文化。
So if you find yourself in the situation where you can't support yourself in American culture at least
因此，如果您发现自己处于至少在美国文化中无法养活自己的境地
you might feel like a failure.
你可能会觉得自己很失败。
You won't feel good.
你不会感觉很好。
Maybe you were doing OK before and then you lost all your money.
也许你以前做得很好，然后你失去了所有的钱。
Not happy.
不开心。
OK.
好的。
So you can say I've really hit rock bottom I've really hit rock bottom.
所以你可以说我真的跌到了谷底 我真的跌到了谷底。
I can't go lower.
我不能再低了。
Imagine falling down into the ocean.
想象一下掉进大海。
You reach the bottom of the ocean.
你到达了海底。
You can't go any deeper.
你不能再深入了。
So you've hit rock bottom you're as far down as you can go.
所以你已经跌到谷底了，你已经尽你所能了。
And it's not a happy thing.
这不是一件快乐的事情。
Now it doesn't have to only be for money.
现在它不必只是为了钱。
So broke is only about only about money but hitting rock bottom is more an emotional thing a thing related
所以破产只是关于金钱，但触底更多是一种情感上的事情。
to your life and the situation of your life.
对你的生活和你的生活状况。
So you could emotionally be completely unhappy because everything went wrong.
所以你可能在情绪上完全不开心，因为一切都出错了。
Maybe you have lots of money.
也许你有很多钱。
You can still say I hit rock bottom I've completely hit rock bottom because for whatever reason you're
你仍然可以说我触底了
extremely depressed you're extremely sad and you feel like there's no lower that you can go.
极度沮丧，您极度悲伤，您觉得自己无法再降下去了。
OK so just to be clear that this one broke is for money.
好的，所以要明确的是，这个坏了是为了钱。
Rock bottom is not.
谷底不是。
So maybe there's a man who lost his lost his job still has money but lost his job then his girlfriend
所以也许有一个人失去了他的爱他的工作还有钱但丢了工作然后是他的女朋友
broke up with him and he still has his own apartment but he just feels like he doesn't know what to
和他分手了，他还有自己的公寓，但他只是觉得他不知道该怎么办
do with his life.
做他的生活。
He has money but he might say I just feel like I've hit rock bottom and I don't know what to do with
他有钱，但他可能会说我只是觉得我已经跌到谷底了，我不知道该怎么办
myself.
我。
That would be a common thing someone in that situation might say it's emotional.
在那种情况下，有人可能会说这是情绪化的，这是很常见的事情。
Negative negative.
负负。
So as a response to that friend might say well you hit rock bottom it's it's all uphill from here.
因此，作为对那个朋友的回应，你可能会说你已经跌入谷底，这一切都是从这里开始的。
That means it can't get any worse.
这意味着它不会变得更糟。
And that's something that people will say too well it can't get any worse.
这是人们会说得太好的事情，它不会变得更糟。
Look at the bright side.
看看好的一面。
It can't get any worse.
它不能变得更糟。
It's all uphill from here.
从这里开始都是上坡路。
If it's really rock bottom OK that would be really optimistic.
如果它真的是最低点，那将是非常乐观的。
That's looking at the bright side looking at the bright side of something means you're looking at that.
那就是看着光明的一面 看着某事的光明面意味着你正在看那个。
Good point.
好点子。
That's there.
就在那里。
Even if it's very small and if it is very small there's a very tiny positive thing about a very bad
即使它非常小，如果它非常小，那么非常糟糕的事情也有非常小的积极意义
situation.
情况。
We often call that the silver as I LV are lining lining silver lining is that if it can't get worse
我们常说的银衬我LV都衬衬银衬就是如果不能变坏
if you've really hit rock bottom then all you have to do is pick yourself up go out there and get a
如果你真的跌到谷底，那么你所要做的就是振作起来，走出去买一个
new job got a new girlfriend.
新工作交了新女朋友。
It's all uphill from here.
从这里开始都是上坡路。
It's going to get better.
它会变得更好。
That's the silver lining that's the silver lining.
那是一线希望，那是一线希望。
Yeah maybe you're right.
是的，也许你是对的。
Thanks.
谢谢。
You made me feel better you made me feel better.
你让我感觉好多了 你让我感觉好多了。
OK.
好的。
So these are the expressions that we can use in negative situations.
所以这些是我们可以在消极情况下使用的表达方式。
These two side and Silver Lining are positive aspects of the negative situation.
这两个方面和一线希望是消极情况的积极方面。
The good points of the bad situation and the bad feeling.
坏情况和坏感觉的优点。
I'd like to stick with this situation for one more expression because I think we need to focus a little
我想在这种情况下再表达一种表达方式，因为我认为我们需要集中注意力
bit more on money.
钱多一点。
We talked about being broke which means you have no money left but there's a more general one that can
我们谈到了破产，这意味着你没有钱了，但有一个更一般的可以
be used to talk about a bad financial situation.
习惯于谈论糟糕的财务状况。
Because saying I'm broke is a little strong and some people might not be willing to express something
因为说我破产有点强，有些人可能不愿意表达什么
that directly so we could say here it was it was really difficult to make ends meet.
直接如此，我们可以在这里说，维持生计真的很困难。
So I had to move back home.
所以我不得不搬回家。
So maybe I was living alone I was living in my own apartment I was doing ok but things got worse.
所以也许我一个人住，我住在自己的公寓里，我过得还好，但事情变得更糟了。
Maybe my financial situation my financial or money situation was not great.
也许我的财务状况我的财务或金钱状况不是很好。
So I was having trouble making ends meet.
所以我很难维持生计。
That might mean I have some money but I can't pay all my bills.
这可能意味着我有一些钱，但我无法支付所有账单。
I have some money but I can't completely support myself.
我有一些钱，但我不能完全养活自己。
So I had to move back in with my parents couldn't make ends meet.
所以我不得不搬回去，因为我的父母无法维持生计。
Another common expression this one is only only for money.
另一种常见的表达方式是这个只是为了钱。
This one is used to talk about being able to afford whatever lifestyle you have.
这个是用来谈论能够负担得起你拥有的任何生活方式的。
If you can make ends meet then maybe you don't need to move in with your parents but if you cannot make
如果你能维持生计，那么也许你不需要搬去和你父母住，但如果你不能维持生计
ends meet you may need to move in with your parents and in American culture that's generally not a good
收支平衡，你可能需要搬去和你的父母住在一起，在美国文化中，这通常不是一件好事
thing.
事物。
People might judge you negatively although in lots of other places in the world it's fine it's fine.
人们可能会对你做出负面评价，尽管在世界上许多其他地方这很好，这很好。
It's interesting how different cultures are different and judge things differently.
有趣的是，不同的文化是如何不同的，并且对事物的判断也不同。
I told some of my my friends in China the story about the man who who was sued by his parents for living
我告诉我在中国的一些朋友，一个男人被父母告过活的故事
at home too long and they couldn't believe that it was real because generally speaking in China if you
在家太久，他们无法相信前夕它是真实的，因为一般来说，如果你在中国
live with your parents that's a good thing because it means you're willing to take care of them and
和父母住在一起是件好事，因为这意味着你愿意照顾他们
generally parents are very happy to have their kids living with them even if they're 30 maybe maybe
通常父母很高兴让他们的孩子和他们一起生活，即使他们已经 30 岁了
even older now that's of course changing a little bit in the modern modern era but it's still quite
现在甚至更老了，这当然在现代时代发生了一些变化，但它仍然相当
different.
不同的。
Americans they generally focus on being very independent is a good word to use independent.
美国人他们通常专注于非常独立，这是一个使用独立的好词。
All right let's go on and look at another situation and learn another useful expression.
好吧，让我们继续看看另一种情况，学习另一种有用的表达方式。